The Tomb of the Cybermen
(Doctor Who 1963 - 05x01 - Whopix fan edit)
赛博人的坟墓
(神秘博士(老版) - 第五季第一集 - Whopix 粉丝剪辑版)
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
【补充听录】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴/翻译】巴蛮子sz
Stand by. Everybody down.
准备，所有人趴下
50 pounds for the first man
to open the doors.
第一个打开大门的奖励50英镑
Miss Kaftan, I must remind you
that I am the leader of the...
Kaftan 小姐，我必须得提醒你，我才是队长...
- What happened?  - I don't know.
- 发生了什么?   - 我不知道
Well, one thing for sure, he's not going to
collect 50 pounds from you or anybody else.
好了，有件事可以肯定，他没法从你这里拿走拿50英镑了
- Quiet. Quiet a minute.  - What's that?
- 安静，安静一下  - 什么声音?
Sounded like an engine.
听起来像是一种引擎
(WHOOSHING)
- Something came down there! Behind that ...
- OK, Viner. Slow down.
- 有什么东西降落了，在后面...  - 好，Viner，悠着点
- I'll take care of this. Jim!
- OK. I've got it!
- 我去看看．Jim!  - 好，我知道了
(LOW VOICES)
Hold it right there, friend.
停住别动，朋友
If you put it like that, I certainly will.
如果你要这样，我当然照作
Hear that, Professor? English.
听到了吗，教授? 是英语
(PARRY) Yes. All right, Hopper.
是的．没事了，Hopper
Thank you.
谢谢你
Who are you and where are you from?
你们是谁，从哪里来?
And you'd better have a good story.
你们最好有一个好的说法
Maybe you'll not get one.
也许你们听不到
Listen, fella.
We're not playing games.
听着，伙计，我们不是在玩游戏
- You'd better listen to him.
- What's been happening over here?
- 你们最好听他的  - 这里发生了什么?
He was killed the moment you men  appeared.
他在你们出现的那一刻被杀了
Ah. And you think we did it?
啊，所以你们认为是我们干的?
Oh no, I can assure you, we had nothing
to do with the death of this man.
不，我可以保证，我们跟这个人的死没有关系
He appears to have been electrocuted.
他看着像是被电击了
Trying to open these doors, perhaps?
是在试图打开这道门吗，或许?
- He seems to know all the answers.
- A wiseguy!
- 他似乎知道所有的答案  - 一个聪明人!
I think this fellow must be
a member of a rival expedition.
我觉得这个家伙肯定是对手探险队的成员
(DOCTOR) Expedition?
探险队?
We've tried to keep it secret.
Unsuccessfully, now it appears.
我们试图保密的，现在看起来没成功
Archaeologist written all over him.
他全身都写着考古学家这几个字
- Really? Does it show?  - You see?
- 真的嘛? 这么明显?   - 你看
It's impossible to keep a secret
in the scientific world.
在科学时间里几乎不可能保守住秘密
- Doctor, what do you mean?
- Tell them, go on, Doctor, tell them.
- 博士，你什么意思?   - 告诉他们吧，博士
No, not until they tell us
the purpose of their expedition.
不，除非他们先告诉我他们探险队的目标
This is an archaeological expedition.
这是一次考古探险
We are searching the universe
for the last remains of the Cybermen.
我们正在宇宙中寻找赛博人的最后遗迹
Cybermen? You mean to say they came from here?
赛博人? 你是说他们来自这里?
Of course. Telos was their home.
当然，Telos 是他们的家
This is the entrance to their city.
这是通向他们城市的入口
We know they died out centuries ago,
我们知道他们几个世纪前就灭绝了
what we don't know is why they died out.
但我们不知道的是，他们为什么灭绝了
Callum, Rogers! Get him back to the rocket.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Callum, Rogers! 来把他抬回火箭去，我很快回来找你们
That's that. Are you coming back
to the rocket with me, Professor?
就是这样．你跟我们回火箭吗，教授?
- What for?
- You're not going on with this, are you?
- 为什么回去?   - 你不打算继续了吧，是吗?
I don't know if these people had
anything to do with it or not,
我不知道这些人跟这事有没有关系
but one of my men was just been killed.
You're not paying that kind of money.
但我的一个人刚刚死了．你并不打算这种情况付钱
- Yes, I suppose that's quite true.
- You think it over.
- 是的，我觉得是这样  - 你想清楚了
Come on, let's go.
We'll wait for you at the ship.
快点，我们走，我们在飞船上等你们
The problem, I take it,
is to open these doors, right?
现在的问题，照我理解，是怎么打开门，对吧?
- Ha! Brilliant.  - That is the problem.
- 哈! 高见  - 那就是问题
And we would prefer it, if you return
to wherever you came from.
而我们更愿意的是，你们从哪里来回那里去
- Not very friendly, are they?
- Do as he says.
- 他们不太友好，是吧?   - 按他说的做
That became impossible the moment
that name was mentioned - Cybermen.
那已经变得不可能了，因为那个名字被提到了 - 赛博人
Cybermen? What are they?
赛博人? 是什么?
I knew they're here on the same quest!
我就知道，他们是为了同一个任务来这里的
No one would come here for any other reason?
就没有人因为别的原因来这个地方吗?
- We must stay!  - Doctor!
- 我们必须留下来!   - 博士!
Must we? I don't like
the look of those things at all.
必须吗? 我完全不喜欢这些事情的样子
We shall stay and help you with your research.
我们会留下来，帮助你们进行研究
Perhaps we don't want help.
也许我们并不需要什么帮助
That's just it. You obviously do.
Now I'm sure we can agree.
这就是了，你们显然需要．我确定我们可以达成一致
- I can open those doors for you.
- It's our problem!
- 我能帮你们打开这道门  - 这是我们自己的事!
Can I suggest you take this ridiculous
expedition of yours off this planet!
我建议你们，把你们这个荒谬的探险从这个星球上带走!
It seems to me we have
as much right here as you have.
在我看来，我们在这里跟你们有一样的权利
Of course you have!
Mr Klieg, must I remind you again...
你们当然有! Klieg 先生，需要我再提醒你一次吗?
that you do not speak for this expedition?
I am its leader.
你并不能代表探险队说话．我才是队长
You and Miss Kaftan
are only here on sufferance.
你和 Kaftan 小姐在这里只是出于我们的宽容
- Thank you. And whose money is paying
for the hire of that rocket?
- (KAFTAN) Mine!
- 多谢提醒．为火箭雇人用的是谁的钱?   - 我的!
I thought I made it clear
that your financial support...
我想我明确过了，你们的经济支持...
did not entitle you to a say
in the running of this expedition!
并没有赋予你们在探险队运作上的发言权!
Of course. It was quite clear.
当然，你说得很清楚
Was it not, Eric?
不是吗，Eric?
Of course.
No one questions your leadership.
当然，没有人质疑你的领导权
Good. That's all settled.
好，那一切都解决了
- And now we shall open these doors.
- What...?
- 那现在我们去把门打开  - 怎么...?
- Careful, man!  - Doctor!
- 小心，朋友!   - 博士!
Perfectly safe now.
现在完全安全了
- You'll be killed!  - Don't touch him!
- 你会死的!   - 别碰他!
- It's beyond my strength.
- Let me, Doctor.
- 我力气不够  - 让我来，博士
I've not had much exercise lately.
我最近没怎么锻炼
Quite. I think here is a gentleman
who could open these doors for us.
是．我觉得这里有个先生可以帮我们把门打开
He is my servant.
I will not have him risk his life.
他是我的仆人，我不会允许他冒生命危险
Surely it was just for such a contingency like this
that you insisted we bring him with us.
就是为了这样的意外，你才坚持让我们把他带在队里的
There's no danger now.
Unless he's afraid.
现在没有危险了，除非他害怕
No, no. He's not afraid.
不不，他不害怕
- Come on.  - No. Wait!
- 快来  - 不，等等
I would be very careful in there
if I were you.
如果我是你，我进去会很小心的
Why weren't Toberman killed?
Why weren't you killed?
为什么 Toberman 没死? 为什么你没死?
The poor fellow who died drained
all the electricity out of his body.
死去的那个可怜家伙，用他的身体把电都吸干了
It's perfectly safe to go in now.
现在进去完全安全了
We're wasting time.
我们在浪费时间
Of course. After you, Professor.
的确是．你先请，教授
But I'd still...
但我还是...
I'd still be very careful if I were you.
Very careful indeed.
如果我是你，我还是会非常小心，真的非常小心
Come on. Let's join them.
快来，跟他们一起
Come on, Victoria.
来吧，Victoria
You look very nice in that dress.
你穿着这条裙子非常漂亮
Thank you.
Don't you think it's a bit...?
谢谢你．你没觉得它有点..
Short? I shouldn't worry.
Look at Jamie's.
短吗? 我就不担心．看看Jamie 的
I'll have you know that... Oh, aye.
我得让你知道...噢，是
Come along. Let's go and see
what the others are doing.
过来，我们去看看其他人在做什么
(VICTORIA)
Mercy! Just look at this place.
怜悯! 看看这个地方
These controls are of earlier dynasties.
这些开关都是上个时代的
Not so early. Look, John...
没那么早．你看，John
I'm quite capable of making
my own deductions! Thank you.
我完全有能力自己来推断! 谢谢你
All right.
好吧
Be careful. There might be danger.
小心，这可能有危险
Don't worry, with Toberman to guard me.
别担心，有 Toberman 护着我呢
What is more important is
to keep an eye on these strangers.
更重要的是，得盯着点这些陌生人
- I tried to...!
- Do not raise your voice.
- 我试图...  - 别那么大声
You will achieve nothing by shouting.
靠大喊大叫是什么也无法达成的
You look after the Doctor
and I will watch the girl.
你看着博士，我盯着这个女孩儿
- And the Scots boy?
- Leave him to Toberman.
- 那个苏格兰男孩儿呢?   - 把他留给 Toberman
Eh, Toberman?
嗯，Toberman?
- But you will be careful and discreet. Understand?
- I understand.
- 但你得小心谨慎点，明白吗?   - 明白
- Did you ever see the like of it, Doctor?
- Not exactly, Jamie, but very nearly.
- 你见过这样的吗，博士?   - 还没有，Jamie，不过很类似
(PARRY) Now that we're all here...
既然我们都在这里...
Now that we're all here, we'd better
take stock of the situation.
既然我们都在这里了，我们最好评估一下情况
This appears to be a dead end.
这边似乎是条死路
The only way out is through that hatch.
唯一出去的路就是那个舱门
- Are there no doors?
- No. Apart from the entrance.
- 没有门吗?   - 没有，只有这个入口
- And the other two, of course.
- Two other doors?
- 和另外两个，当然了  - 另外还有两个?
Yes. One in that section
and one in that section over there.
是的，一个在这一段，还有一个在那边那段
Activated, I imagine, by this
simple logical system here.
激活方法，我估计，是用这边的简单符号逻辑系统
Here we are, I think.
就这里，我想
(BLEEPING)
Yes, splendid! A simple logical gate.
是的，太棒了!一个简单的逻辑门
Doctor, you seem to be
very familiar with this place.
博士，你似乎非常熟悉这个地方
Not really. It's all based on symbolic logic.
还真不是，这全都是基于符号逻辑
The same as you use in computers.
跟你们在电脑里用的一样
The opening mechanism of this door -
an OR gate, as you call it.
打开这道门的机制，是一道或门，你们的叫法是这样的
Yes, I can see that, but how did you know
in the first place?
是的，我看得出来，但你一开始是怎么知道的?
I use my own special technique.
我使用我自己的特殊技巧
Really? And may we know what that is?
真的? 那可以告诉我们是什么吗?
Keeping my eyes open
and my mouth shut.
睁大眼睛，闭上嘴巴
We are too many to explore together.
I think we'd better divide up.
我们人太多了，难以一起探索．我想我们最好分开
If you, Mr Viner, would take that door with...
如果你，Viner 先生，走那个门，与...
- Jamie.  - Jamie and Mr Haydon.
- 我叫Jamie  - 与Jamie 和 Haydon 先生一起
Mr Klieg, the Doctor and myself
will be a party.
Klieg，以及博士和我一队
- What about us?
- I think the women should better to remain here.
- 我们怎么办?   - 我觉得女人最好留在这里
Rubbish! We can make a party.
胡说! 我们可以组一队
Certainly. With Toberman to guard us,
we need fear no one.
当然．有 Toberman 保护，我们谁也不怕了
Mr Klieg, will you take them with you?
Klieg 先生，你会带他们一起吗?
- I prefer to stay here.  - As you wish.
- 我情愿留在这里  - 随便你了
Mr Viner, will you go along with the women?
Viner 先生，你可以跟女人们一起走吗?
- If you like.
- Get back to the spacecraft by 16.30.
- 随你安排  - 要在16:30回到飞船
You all know the temperature drop at night,
你们都知道，气温会在晚间下降
so we'll meet back here at 16.25.
If anyone is missing...
所以我们在16:25回这里会合．如果有人失踪...
that gives us an hour to look for them
before we have to leave.
这可以给我们一个小时去寻找他们，之后就必须得离开了
Come on then. We might as well
try that opening over there.
那就来吧．我们可能得试试那边的开关
We'd better keep close together.
我们最好待在一起
I'm all right, thank you.
我没事，谢谢你
- Come on, Jamie.  - Right.
- 快来，Jamie  - 好
Now to concentrate on this, whatever it is.
现在聚焦一下这个东西，不管它是什么
This hatch must lead somewhere
这个舱门肯定通向某个地方
and there must be
some opening mechanism.
而且肯定有某种打开机制
What was that about
symbolic logic? Any ideas?
那跟符号逻辑有什么关系? 谁知道?
No, not really.
不，不怎么知道
I think it's time
we gave Mr Klieg a chance
我看是时候给 Klieg 先生一个机会了
to show off his archaeological skills.
让他来炫耀一下他的考古技巧
Come on. Right in.
快来，进来了
Where's Toberman?
Toberman 去哪儿了?
I sent him to join the others.
我让他加入其他组了
We do not need protection
now that you are with us.
既然你跟我们在一起，我们不需要保护了
Yes. Well, shall we commence?
是的．怎样，我们开始吧?
Everything must be carefully
measured and recorded.
每样东西都必须精心测量、仔细记录
What is this room?
这是个什么房间
I don't know. Possibly this is
where the Cybermen are made.
我不知道．也许这是赛博人被造出来的地方
I wonder what this is.
我很好奇这是什么
Do you mind? You're in my way.
Just go over there.
抱歉，你妨碍到我了．去那边吧
Oh, fiddle!
噢，瞎搞
Could this not be the purpose of the room?
这可能是这个房间的目的吗?
Yes?
什么
A Cyberman would stand
in that form and be...
赛博人就站在那里面，然后就被...
Well, revitalised.
嗯，焕发生机了
Yes, that's reasonable.
是的，有道理
These projectors probably meant to fire in
some neuro-electric potential.
这些射枪很可能是用来注入神经电势能的
That's it. I think you're right.
是的，我觉得你说得对
Revitalising is just what I need.
我正好也需要重新焕发生机
Mercy! The Cybermen
must have been giants!/
天呐，赛博人一定都是巨人!
Well?
怎样?
The basis of this code
is binary to digital conversion,
这段编码的基础是二进制到数字转换
with an intervening step involving
a sort of Whitehead logic.
夹杂了一个中间步骤，这个步骤涉及某种怀特黑德逻辑
When this Bourrier series is complete,
then there is no more to be done.
当Bourrier系列完成的时候，就搞定了fixme
- Yes, but why do it at all?
- Really, Doctor?
- 是，但为什么要弄那个?   - 真的吗，博士?
For an archaeologist, you seem to
be curiously lacking in curiosity.
作一个考古学家，你居然缺乏好奇心
Some things are better left undone
and I have a feeling this is one of them.
有些东西最好别动，而我有种感觉，这就是其中之一
What do you mean by that?
这么说是什么意思?
- It's all too easy, isn't it?  - Easy?
- 所有这些都太容易了，是不?   - 容易?
I wouldn't call this an easy survey. Would you?
我不会把这称为容易的调查．你会?
Everything is designed to keep their secrets,
whatever they are, insoluble.
所有这些的设计目的，都是为了让他们的秘密无法解开
Insoluble? Oh, I wouldn't say that.
无法解开? 噢，我不会这么说
Take this mathematical sequence for example.
I'm really no nearer to its solution.
拿这个数学序列来说，我真的离解开它还远着呢
I've tried every combination.
It's hardly call that easy.
我试了所有的组合了．真没法把这说是“容易”
Yes. Well, what you've done here
is mostly right.
是．不过，你在这里已经完成的绝大部分都是对的
- Thank you (!)
- You see, any progressive series
- 谢谢你  - 你看，任何递进的系列
can be converted into binary notation.
都可以被转换为二进制写法
If you take the sum of the integrets
如果你对整数求和
and express the result as a power series,
再将结果表达为幂数系列
then the indices show the basic binary blocks.
然后指数就会呈现基本的二元块了
(这一段完全不懂，瞎翻译，抱歉)
Only I wouldn't do it if I were you.
Oh, I really wouldn't do it.
只是我就不会这么做，如果我是你的话．噢，我真的不会
Of course! You're right!
当然! 你是对的!
(LOW HUMMING)
Look! Sum between limits of one and 91
看! 对1和91求和
integral into power series... Yes, yes!
积分到幂数系列，对了，对了!
Then you differentiate...
然后再进行差分...
You fool! Why couldn't you leave it alone?
你个蠢人! 怎么你就不能别碰它?
- What's happening?  - I don't know.
- 怎么了?   - 我不知道
Perhaps the Cybermen aren't as
quite dormant as you imagine.
也许赛博人不像我们想的那样完全在休眠
Yes, we must find out
what's happened to the others.
是了，我们必须看看其他人怎么样了
- Is that all?  - Aye.
- 都试过了?   - 是
All except this big button here.
What does that do?
都试过了，除了这个大按钮，它是干什么的?
I'm not sure, but we'll find out.
我不确定，但我们会弄明白
I'm going to trace the source
of these shapes.
我打算跟踪一下这些形体的来源
There must be a projector somewhere.
肯定某个地方有个投射器
- When I give the word, press the button.
- The big one?
- 我喊的时候，就按那个按钮  - 大这个?
Yes. Maybe it works in conjunction with the others.
也许它要跟其它的一起才能生效
- Right. Ready when you are.
- OK. Go ahead.
- 好，等你准备好了  - 好，开始吧
- Jamie, don't touch that control!
- I already have.
- Jamie，别碰那个开关!   - 我已经碰了
- What's the matter, Doctor?
- Which one was it?
- 什么情况，博士  - 刚才是哪个?
Which one what?
哪个怎么了?
Aaagh!
啊!
- Careful, Doctor!  - It's all right. I...
- 小心，博士!   - 没事，我...
I think it's all right now.
我觉得现在没事了
Yes. You see. It's just a mock-up, a model.
是的，你看．这只是一个样机，一个模型
Don't touch that!
That gun may be wired up too.
别碰那个! 那把枪可能还没断开
- It's a trap.  - No, I don't think so.
- 这是个陷阱  - 不，我不觉得
It's a testing room for weapons.
这是一间武器测试室
This is a purely robotic Cyberman.
这纯粹只是个机械赛博人
There's no human material in it at all.
里面没有任何人类材料
It's a target for weapons.
它是武器的靶子
Let's get back to the control room
with this poor fellow.
我们回到控制室吧，带上这个可怜的家伙
What's that?
那是什么?
(JAMIE) Some wee creature
I found on the floor.
我在地板上找到的小怪物
It's a fossil.
像是个化石
Victoria, be careful! Let me see that.
Victoria, 小心! 让我看看
Yes, it's certainly inactive,
but it's not a fossil.
是的，它的确是不活跃了，但并不是个化石
Wait a minute.
等一下
Yes. Here we are.
是的，我们找到了
Yes.
是的
It's a Cybermat.
这是个赛博鼠
What's a Cybermat?
赛博鼠是什么?
It's one of those...
I'd leave it alone if I were you.
它是一种...反正如果我是你就不会去碰它
I just don't understand this code.
我死活搞不明白这段编码
The sequence doesn't make complete sense.
这个序列完全没有意义
You, a logician, can't understand it?
你，一个逻辑学家，搞不明白它?
- You must.
- But in the time we have...
- 你必须  - 但我们就这么些时间...
We have plenty of time. You will see.
我们有很多时间，你会发现的
- Lay him down there.
- What has happened to him?
- 把他在这里放下吧  - 他怎么了?
There's been a terrible accident.
He's been shot.
发生了一次可怕的意外，他被枪击了
Right. We're all here, it seems.
Would you all sit down for a moment?
好，看起来我们都到了．你们都坐下来歇一会儿吗?
Toberman?
Toberman?﻿
Mr Klieg?
Klieg 先生?
Leave me alone. Can't you see I'm working?
别烦我，你没看见我正在工作吗?
Have you forgotten
the purpose of this expedition?
你已经忘记这次探险的目的了?
This directly concerns my expedition.
You will kindly take your place.
这直接关系到我的探险．请你去就坐
Right. I'll come straight to the point.
好，那我就开门见山了
I have reluctantly decided to abandon
the expedition and return to Earth.
我很不情愿地决定，放弃这次探险，回地球去
- It's impossible!
- I feel just as strongly about it as you.
- 这不可能!   - 我对此也有与你们一样强烈的感觉
This expedition has been
my dream for many years.
这次探险是我多年的梦想
There were some, like Mr Viner,
said more preparation was needed -
曾经有些人，比如 Viner 先生，说过需要做更多准备
more men and equipment.
更多的人和设备
I refused to heed their warnings,
and the result is that two have died.
我没有重视这些警告，结果是有两个人死掉了
I'm sorry, but we must leave
at the first available conjunction.
我很抱歉，但我们必须在第一次有可用连接时就离开
We'll take back all we can
for further study of course.
当然，我们尽可能带走一些东西，以供后续研究
But that is my decision
and that is what we must do.
但这是我的决定，也是我们必须要做的
- I insist that...!
- My decision is final!
- 我坚持认为...  - 我这是最后决定!
We leave when the north hemisphere
is properly tangential,
当北半球转到合适的切向时，我们就走
which will be at 18.42.
也就是大约在18:42
Ah, Captain Hopper. Just the man.
啊，Hopper 队长，正要找你呢
- Can you be ready to blast off at 18.42?
- No.
- 你能准备好在18:42升空吗?   - 不能
I beg your pardon. Did I hear you right?
对不起，我没听错吧?
You are paid to take orders.
你拿了钱，就得遵从命令
Not impossible ones.
但做不到的命令就遵从不了
It's the fuel pumps.
Some character has balled-up the lot.
是燃油泵，某个人把它们破坏了
- What?  - Or someTHING.
- 什么?   - 或者是某个东西
Whatever it is, it's practically wrecked
our chances of leaving this planet.
不管是什么，基本上把我们离开这个星球的机会给破坏了
There's no doubt about it.
The major workings lie below.
毫无疑问，主要的工事都在下面
There are metal caverns
down there, all interconnected.
下面有两个金属窟窿，相互连接
If only we can get down to them.
要是我们能下到那里就好了
That's it! I've got it!
对了，我明白了!
Finally, a Boolean function
of symbolic logic.
最终，还是一个符号逻辑的布尔函数
- Logical, yes, but...
- Everything yields to logic.
- 有逻辑的，是，但是...  - 一切都暗合逻辑
- Our basic assumption, Doctor  - Really.
- 这是我们基本的假设，博士  - 真是
Six, cap, B4...
6与B4取交集
if and only if C
当且仅当C
is cap function of 2A.
得到交集函数2A
I think perhaps your logic
is wearing a little thin.
我看你的逻辑有点站不住脚啊
I must have made a mistake.
I'll do it again more carefully.
我肯定犯了一个错误．我再仔细来一遍
Six, cap, B4...
6与B4取交集
if and only if C...
当且仅当C
is cap faction of... Ah, that's it!
得到交集函数...啊，就是它了
2F, not 2A.
是 2F 不是 2A
(WHIRRING)
I've done it! I've done it!
我搞定了! 我搞定了!
- Congratulations!  - But, Doctor, you...
- 恭喜恭喜  - 但是，博士，你...
Excellent. Now to work.
很好，现在去干活吧
It'll be extremely cold down there.
We shall all need to put on warm clothing.
下面极其冷，我们都得穿上保暖的衣服
Mr Viner, would you please get the anoraks?
Viner 先生，你能去把防寒服取来吗?
- Just a moment. Are we all going down?
- There's safety in numbers.
- 等一下，我们都要下去吗  - 人多安全些
- The women as well?
- They will of course stay up here.
- 女人也下去?   - 她们当然留在这上面
In case of trouble, contact the rocket.
万一遇到麻烦，联系火箭
- I'm coming down with you.
- But my dear young lady...
- 我跟你们下去  - 但是我亲爱的小姐...
- You heard me, Professor.  - Victoria.
- 你听到我的话了，教授  - Victoria
You will be much safer up here.
你在上面这里会安全得多
- But, Doctor...  - And much more use to us.
- 但是，博士...  - 而且对我们更有用
- I don't see...
- By keeping an eye on things.
- 我看不出...  - 有些事情可以盯着点
Please.
拜托了
- All right.  - Thank you.
- 没事了  - 谢谢你
(PARRY) If we're all ready,
I shall lead the descent.
如果我们都准备好了，我带头下去了
Be ready to go back the instant I give the word.
做好准备，万一有问题听我消息就马上回来
- You know what to do?  - The hatch?
- 你知道该怎么弄吗?   - 舱门?
Mr Toberman?
Toberman 先生呢?
He stays with me.
他跟我一起留下来
Then I stay here too.
那我也留在这里
Of course. I am being selfish.
当然．我这样太自私了
His strength will be useful to you
down there. He must go down.
他的力气在下面对你们有用，他必须下去
Go down, Toberman.
下去吧，Toberman
Remember what I said. Be very careful.
记住我说的，千万小心
(KAFTAN) It seems we are left alone to wait.
看来就剩我们在这里等了
Captain Hopper brought food
from the rocket. You would like some?
Hopper 队长从火箭那边带来了食物，你要来点吗?
Rather! I'm ravenous.
要! 我饿死了
Hurry up, we've no time to linger!
快点，我们没时间磨蹭了!
It's extremely cold down here,
even with these anoraks.
下面极其寒冷，这些保暖服也太不管用
(JAMIE) You obviously knew what to expect.
你显然早知道会有什么
Well, which way do we go?
喏，我们走那条路?
I don't know. Let's try this one.
我不知道，我们试试这边
Yes.
好
Hey, what on Earth?!
嘿，这是什么鬼?
(PARRY) Behold, gentlemen,
the tombs of the Cybermen.
看啊，先生们，赛博人的坟墓
(JAMIE) Tombs? I don't see any tombs.
坟墓? 我没看到什么坟墓
There, Jamie.
那儿，Jamie
Frozen forever.
永久冻住的
All their evil locked away with them.
他们的邪恶也一并被锁住了
And so it must remain.
而且必须一直保持这样
Like a gigantic honeycomb.
就像一个巨大的蜂巢
Like bees waiting for the signal
to arise from their winter sleep.
就像蜜蜂一样，等着一个信号，从他们的冬眠中苏醒
A signal they are never going to get.
他们永远也不会得到这个信号
We'd better get busy.
Everything must be recorded.
我们动作得快点，所有东西都要录下来
It's too cold to remain here for long
这里太冷了，可没法待太久
Unless we find some way to warm things up.
除非我们能找到什么方法让这里暖和起来
You have hardly touched your coffee.
你的咖啡没怎么动啊
It must be cold by now.
这会儿肯定已经冷了
You would like some more?
你还要再来一点吗?
No, thank you. I'm much warmer now.
不用了，谢谢你，我现在暖和多了
That's good.
那就好
I...
我...
feel so sleepy.
觉得好困
(WHIRRING)
(CLANG)
- What was that?
- It sounded like the hatch.
- 那是什么声音?   - 听起来好像是舱门
It's closed!
它被关上了!
What's the use?
We're trapped down here now.
关上做什么? 我们现在被困在下面了
We'll never survive in this cold.
在这么冷的地方我们没法存活
Better get back.
最好是回去
Well?
怎样?
It's closed. What have they done that for?
What are they playing at up there?
被关上了．他们为什么这么做? 他们在上面玩什么啊?
Maybe it wasn't them. Where's Jamie?
也许不是他们．Jamie 那里去了?
He went up the ladder to try it.
他上梯子去试试
Professor. Professor, listen to me,
for heaven's sake!
教授，教授，听我说，老天
The hatch is down again.
We're trapped down here.
舱门又降下来了，我们被困在下面了
But some of my party
are up there. Are you sure?
但我有一部分人在上面．你确定吗?
Of course I'm sure. You know how heavy it is.
我当然确定，你知道它有多重
It's down now. We must do something!
现在关上了．我们必须做点什么!
I'll give us a couple of hours in here at most.
我觉得我们在这里最多能待几个小时
Mr Klieg doesn't seem to be very worried.
Klieg 似乎并不怎么担心
No, I'm not, Doctor.
不，我不担心，博士
It won't open and I can't make them hear.
它不会打开，我也没法让他们听见
There is an easy way out of our situation.
有一个简单的方法跳出当前的困境
- You've found something?
- Of cource, you're forgetting the logic.
- 你发现了什么吗?   - 当然， 你们忘记了逻辑
If it closes, it can be opened
- from here.
如果它关上了，就可以被打开 - 从这里打开
Conveniently labelled
in symbolic logic, I noticed.
已经很贴心地用符号逻辑标上了 - 我注意到了
Right. Are we ready?
I shall now operate the sequence.
对．我们准备好了，我要开始操作了
If it is the opening device.
只要这是开启装置
It's obvious an opening device
of some kind, Doctor.
这很显然是某种开启装置，博士
I don't know how you can be
so blasted calm about it!
我不知道你们怎么能这么冷静!
I'll see if it works then.
我来看看它是否能工作
Go ahead!
开始吧!
Nothing happening out here!
这里什么也没有发生!
It doesn't work.
它没起作用
Water!
水!
- It's getting warmer.
- The ice is melting.
- 变热了  - 冰在融化
Hey, look behind you!
嘿，看看你后面
Look!
看
Look at the honeycomb.
快看蜂巢
There's something inside.
里面有什么东西
They're... They're Cybermen.
那些是...那些是赛博人
Jamie, come back!
Jamie, 回来!
It is them.
是他们
Gentlemen, they are perfect.
先生们，他们是完好的
This is unique in archaeology.
这在考古学上是独一无二的
No!
不!
No! They're moving!
不! 他们在动了!
We must shut it down.
我们必须关掉它
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING WINDS DOWN)
What are you doing? Keep away from that!
你在干什么? 离那个远点!
No.
不
- What are you doing?
- Keep away! I shall not hesitate to kill!
- 你在干什么!   - 一边去! 我开枪是不会犹豫的!
For the last time, I'm asking you
to keep away from those controls.
最后一次， 我叫你离开那些开关
No!
不!
Viner!
Viner!​
You've killed him!
你杀了他!
- He's mad.  - Jamie!
- 他疯了  - Jamie!
Haydon dead, now Viner.
Haydon 已经死了，现在又是 Viner
What kind of man are you?
你是个什么人啊?
Back! Keep back!
后退! 后退!
Let's see what happens.
我们看看会发生什么
As the Professor says, this is
a unique archaeological event.
正如教授所说，这是考古学上的大新闻
It would be such a pity to miss it.
要是错过的话就太遗憾了
(LOUD WHIRRING)
Doctor, I have a feeling
that man's planned it all.
博士，我有一种感觉，那个人早就计划好了
He knew that wouldn't open the hatch.
他知道那个东西不能打开舱门
- So did I, Jamie.  - You knew, Doctor?
- 我也觉得，Jamie  - 你早知道，博士?
I wanted to know what he was up to.
我想要知道他在谋划什么
- And now you know, Doctor.
- We know nothing.
- 现在你知道了，博士  - 我们什么也不知道
This is the action of a lunatic.
这是一个疯子才会干的事情
Lunatic? Not at all, Professor.
A necessary detail, that's all.
疯子? 完全不是，教授．这是必要的步骤，仅此而已
But why?
但为什么?
Logic, my dear Professor, logic and power.
逻辑，我亲爱的教授，逻辑和权力
On Earth, the Brotherhood of Logicians
在地球上，逻辑兄弟会
is the greatest man intelligence
ever assembled.
集结了最聪明的人
But that's not enough. We need power -
但这还不够，我们需要权力
power to put our ability into action.
可以将我们的能力变成行动的权力
The Cybermen have this power.
I have come to find it and use it.
赛博人有这个力量，我就是来找到它利用它的
So that was your motive
in financing my expedition!
这就是你资助我们探险队的动机!
Precisely. Your complete lack of administration
made it ideal for our purpose.
正是．你完全缺乏管理，这对于我们的目的相当理想
You think the Cybermen will help you?
你觉得赛博人会帮助你?
Of course. I shall be their resurrector.
当然，我是复兴他们的人
Look!
快看!
- Keep still!   - Behind you!
- 待着别动!   - 在你后面!
That thing! It's come alive!
那个东西! 它活过来了!
You are so simple. You don't really expect
to take me in with a trick like that?
你太单纯了，真的别想用这样的技巧诓骗我
It's true! Look!
是真的，快看!
- Will nothing keep you still?
- Will you please look?!
- 没什么能让你安静吗?   - 求你能看一下吗?
(BEEPING)
Any more trouble and I'll take drastic steps.
再要捣乱，我就要采取极端措施了
We won't allow a little girl
to interfere with our plan!
我们不会容许一个小女儿来破坏我们的计划!
Aaagh!
啊!
(BEEPING WINDS DOWN...)
(..AND STOPS)
What is it?
那是什么?
I think it's their leader,
their Controller, Jamie.
我猜是他们的头儿，他们的管理员，Jamie
(CONTROLLER) You belong to us.
你属于我们
You shall be like us.
你会跟我们一样
Can we not make a run for it, Doctor?
我们就不能逃跑吗，博士?
No. We wouldn't even reach the ladder.
It's too risky.
不，我们甚至都到不了梯子那里．这太冒险了
What can we do?
我们能做什么?
Play for time. Wait for our chance.
Leave it to me.
拖延时间，等待机会．这交给我吧
Excuse me? May I ask a question?
对不起，我可以问一个问题吗?
Why did you submit yourself to freezing?
你们为什么把自己冷冻起来?
You don't have to answer that,
if you don't want to
你们不一定要回答，如果你们不想的话
To survive.
为了生存
Our history computer
has full details of you.
我们的电脑里有对你的详细描述
Oh? How?
噢? 怎样的?
We know of your intelligence.
我们知道你的智慧
Oh. Thank you very much.
哦，非常感谢
Ah, yes. The lunar surface.
啊，是的，月球表面
Our machinery had stopped
我们的机器停了
and our supply of replacements
been depleted.
我们的替代品供应也耗尽了
So that's why you attacked the moonbase.
所以你们就去攻击月球基地
You had destroyed our first planet
你摧毁了我们的第一颗行星
and we were becoming extinct.
我们就逐渐灭绝了
What difference does capturing us make?
You'll still become extinct.
把我们抓起来有什么用? 你们还是会灭绝
We will survive.
我们会活下去
You will become the first
of a new race of Cybermen.
你们会变成第一批新一代赛博人
You will return to Earth
and control it.
你们将回到地球，掌控它
But we're humans. We're not like you.
但我们是人类，跟你们不一样
You will be.
你们会一样的
Oh. No. Keep away!
噢，不要，离我远点!
Keep away!
离远点!
Keep away...!
离远点...
It's very quiet down there.
下面非常安静
Yeah. Too quiet.
是啊，太安静了
- Something must have happened.
- How long they been down?
- 肯定发生什么事情了  - 他们下去多久了?
About an hour.
大概一个小时
That's too long. I'm going down.
那太长了．我下去看看
You are a logician.
你是个逻辑学家
Our race is also logical.
我们种族也是讲求逻辑的
You will be the leader of the new race.
你将是新种族的领袖
You will listen to my proposals, then?
那，你们将会听我的提议啰?
Yes. We will listen.
是的，我们会听
But first you will be altered.
但首先你得被改造
Altered?
改造?
You have fear.
你有恐惧
We will eliminate fear from your brain.
我们将从你的大脑里移除恐惧
Yes. You will be the first.
是的，你将是第一个
And you will be the next.
而你将是下一个
No! No! Aagh!
不，不! 啊!
You will be like us.
你将会跟我们一样
To die is unnecessary.
死亡是不必要的
You will be frozen
你们将会被冻结
and placed in our tombs
置入我们的坟墓中
until we are ready to use you.
直到我们准备好使用你们
Your lives will be suspended.
你们的生命将会暂停
Prepare the tombs.
准备好墓室
They really mean it.
They're going to freeze us.
他们来真的，这是要冰冻我们
- Not me.  - No, they're coming back.
- 对我休想  - 糟，他们要回来了
Come on, you guys. Run for it!
快点，伙计们，跑啊!
Jamie!
Jamie!﻿
Look at that smoke.
看那个烟
(JAMIE) Victoria!
Victoria!﻿
Come on, Mr Parry. Come on, quick!
快啊，Parry 先生，加油，快!
The Cybermen! They're right behind us.
赛博人! 他们就在我们后面
As soon as the Doctor's up,
close down the hatch!
等博士一上来，就关闭舱门!
- OK!  - Stand by!
- 好!   - 准备!
Oh! Aagh! He's got my leg!
噢，啊! 他抓住了我的腿!
Doctor, come on!
博士，加油!
- Come on!  - It's no use.
- 加油!   - 没有用
Jim, close the hatch!
Jim, 关掉舱门!
(CALLUM) Got him!
搞定他了!
(BANGING)
It was horrible. It was so strong!
太可怕了，它这么强!
It's all right, Victoria.
You're all right now.
没事了，Victoria. 你现在安全了
That was a near thing. Is anyone missing?
刚才太险了，有谁失踪吗?
Yes. Klieg and Toberman.
They're still down there!
有，Klieg 和 Toberman．他们还在下面!
Don't open it. It may be the Cybermen.
别打开，可能是赛博人
No. No, it's too soft.
不，不像，太轻了
- It must be Toberman and Klieg.
- Are you crazy?
- 肯定是 Toberman 和 Klieg  - 你疯了?
You're right. We can't leave them
down there even if they are killers.
你是对的．我们不能把他们扔在下面，就算他们是杀人犯
They're both probably frozen solid by now.
他们俩这会儿肯定被完全冻住了
You must let them up. They must be saved.
你必须让他们上来，必须要救他们
Yes, they're more dangerous
down there than up here.
是的，下面比上面这里危险得多
What? OK. Jim?
什么? 好．Jim?
Right.
马上
(KNOCKING)
Okey. Let her go.
好， 打开它
Excuse me, please.
对不起，让让
Shut it! Shut it quick!
关上! 快关上!
- Where's Toberman?  - They've got him.
- Toberman 在哪里?   - 他们抓住他了
You still think you can form an alliance
with the Cybermen, Mr Klieg?
你还觉得你能跟赛博人结成联盟吗，Klieg先生?
If only I'd been in a stronger position
to bargain with them.
我要是在一个更有利的位置，就可以和他们谈条件了
You must be out of your mind, Klieg
你肯定是脑子进水了， Klieg
You're not in any position
to bargain with anybody right now.
你现在没有同任何人谈条件的资本
What are we going to do with them?
我们打算拿他们怎么样?
I'd feel much happier
if they weren't in here.
如果他们不在这里，我会高兴得多
What about the testing room?
There's only one door. They can't get out.
测试室怎么样? 它只有一个门，他们出不去
Good idea. They'll be quite safe in there.
好主意．他们在那里面比较安全
- Callum!  - Right.
- Callum!  - 好
Mr Klieg?
Klieg 先生?
Miss Kaftan.
Kaftan 小姐
These humanoids are not like us.
这些人类跟我们不一样
They still have fear.
他们还是有恐惧感
Place the Cybermats on the runway.
把赛博鼠放到轨道上
Cybermats will attack.
赛博鼠将发起攻击
Oh!
呵!
I'm on your side, remember?
我是你这边的，记得吗?
Hey, why didn't you wake me?
嘿，你为什么不叫醒我?
I should have been on watch
half an hour ago.
在半小时前就应该轮到我放哨了
- I thought you should rest.  - Why me?
- 我觉得你应该多休息  - 为什么是我?
No reason really.
没什么原因
Oh, I think I know.
Was it because I'm...?
噢，我想我知道了．是不是因为我...?
Well, if you are 450 years old,
you need a great deal of sleep.
嗯，如果你已经450岁了，你需要睡很多觉
Well, that's very considerate of you, Victoria,
啊，你真能体谅人，Victoria
but, between you and me,
I'm really quite lively actually -
但，别告诉别人啊，我其实很有生命力的 -
all things being considered.
不管从哪方面来说
Are you happy with us, Victoria?
你跟我们在一起快乐吗，Victoria?
Yes, I am.
嗯，是的
At least, I would be if my father were here.
至少，如果我父亲也在这里我会更快乐
Yes, I know. I know.
是的，我知道，我知道
I wonder what he'd thought
if he could see me now.
我想知道，如果他现在能见到我，他会怎么想
You miss him very much, don't you?
你非常想念他，是不是?
It's only when I close my eyes...
嗯，每当我闭上眼睛
I can still see him standing there.
我都能看到他站在那里
Before those horrible
Dalek creatures came to the house.
在那些 Dalek 怪物来到我们屋之前
He was a very kind man.
他是一个很善良的人
I shall never forget him. Never.
我永远也不会忘记他，永远
No, of course you won't.
不会，你当然不会的
But, you know, the memory of him
won't always be a sad one.
但是，你知道吗，对他的记忆并不会总是悲伤的
I think it will.
我觉得会的
You can't understand, being so ancient.
你不会明白了，你这么古老
- Eh?  - I mean old.
- 嗯?   - 我是说年长
You probably can't remember your family.
你可能都不记得你的家庭了
Oh, yes, I can when I want to.
哦，记得，当我想要想起，就能
That's the point.
就是这个意思
I have to really want to
bring them back in front of my eyes.
我只是必须得在脑海里把他们带到我的眼前
The rest of the time
they sleep in my mind and I forget.
其它时候他们沉睡在我的意识里，我就忘记了
And so will you. Oh, yes, you will.
你也会这样的．噢，是的，你也会的
You'll find there's so much else
to think about, to remember.
你会发现有太多其它的事情要去考虑，去记忆
Our lives are different to anybody else's.
我们每个人的生命跟其他任何一个人都不同的
That's the exciting thing.
这是最让人激动的地方
There's nobody in the universe
can do what we're doing.
宇宙中没有谁能做我们在做的事情
You must get some sleep,
你必须去睡一会儿了
and let this poor old man stay awake.
让这个可怜的老人醒着吧
Jamie, Victoria, Callum, wake up!
Jamie, Victoria, Callum, 醒醒!
- Wake up!  - What is it?
- 醒醒!   - 怎么了?
Callum. Callum.
Callum. Callum.﻿
(VICTORIA) Those terrible things.
这些可怕的东西
Don't move, Callum. Don't move.
别动，Callum, 别动
Get back to the controls, all of you.
回到开关那边去，你们全部
Steady. Don't make any sudden movements.
Parry, wake up.
慢点，别陡然乱动．Parry, 醒醒
Don't panic. Come back with us. Steady.
别惊慌，到我们这边来，慢点
We'll all go in the other room
and lock them out.
我们全部去另外那个房间，把它们关在外面
Aagh!
啊!
Let's get out of here.
我们离开这里
The main doors.
大门
No!
不要!
Oh! Oh, Doctor, we're trapped!
噢! 噢，博士，我们被困住了!
Back against the controls, everybody.
背靠控制台，所有人
Here.
这里
Give me a hand, quick.
帮我一把，快
Lay this down on the ground. Come on!
把这个铺设在地板上，快点
- Doctor?  - Come on!
- 博士?   - 快点!
Let's blast the filthy things!
我们轰掉这些丑恶的东西!
You're wasting your time.
There are too many of them! Come back!
你是在浪费自己的时间．它们太多了，回来!
- There you are. You see?
- What are those creatures?
- 这下好了，看到了吧?  - 那些怪物是什么?
Well, they're...
嗯，它们是...
They're a form of metallic life.
它们是一种金属生命形式
They home on human brainwaves, and attack.
它们朝人类脑电波前进，实施攻击
Urgh!
呃!
Are they safe now?
现在它们没危险了吗?
Quite safe now. The power cable
generated an electrical field
现在相当安全了．这根电缆产生了一个电场
that confused their tiny metal minds.
搅乱了它们那金属的小脑袋
You might say that they've had
a complete metal breakdown.
你可以说它们完全是“金属崩溃”了
(博士在这里借用了 metal breakdown
与 mental breakdown (精神崩溃)发音相近的特点)
- Ooh.  - I'm so sorry, Jamie.
- 哦   - 真的很抱歉，Jamie
What about Klieg and Kaftan?
They've probably been attacked as well.
Klieg 和 Kaften 怎么样了? 他们很可能也一样被攻击了
- The testing room.
- Come on. Mind your feet.
- 测试室  - 快点，小心脚下
Most ingenious, Doctor.
真是聪明啊，博士
Now let's see what you can do against this.
现在我们来看看你怎么对付这个
Watch out, Doctor!
小心，博士!
The humanoids must first be destroyed.
必须首先消灭这些人类
You will re-enter cells
to conserve energy.
为了节省能力， 你们得重新进入格子间
Keep back!
后退!
Your gun.
你的枪
You've killed him, you murderer.
你杀了他，你这个杀人犯
- No. He is fortunate. I spared him.
- You mean you missed him.
- 不．他很幸运．我饶了他  - 你是说你没打中吧
Silence! I could have destroyed him
if I wanted to.
闭嘴! 我本可以杀了他的，如果我想的话
- Shall I kill them now?
- No, that will not be necessary.
- 我现在该杀了他们吗?   - 不，并没有必要
I'm sure the Cybermen
will have a use for them.
我能肯定，赛博人能好好利用他们
You will make excellent
experimental specimens.
你们将成为绝佳的实验样品
Oh, let me help him, please!
噢，让我帮他一下，拜托!
No tricks.
别耍花招
Still think you can bargain with the Cybermen?
还觉得你可以跟赛博人谈条件?
Certainly. This time on our terms.
当然，这次得按我们的条件来
I wish to speak to the Controller.
我要同管理员谈话
I wish to speak to the Controller!
He is now prepared.
现在他已经准备好了
Release him.
放把出去吧
They're coming.
他们来了
Now, gentlemen, you will see how
I shall use the power of the Cybermen.
现在，先生们，你们将会见识到我是如何利用赛博人的力量的
Use, maybe, but you'll never
control the Cybermen.
利用，有可能; 但你永远别想控制住赛博人
- Behind you.  - Stop!
- 在你后面  - 停下!
You know what this can do to you.
你知道这个会把你怎么样
Toberman, it is good that you are back.
Toberman, 你回来真是太好了
Watch them.
看着他们
- Doctor, he seems er...
- Yes, Jamie, yes.
- 博士，他似乎...  - 是的，Jamie, 是的
I shall let you be revitalised, to survive.
我该让你充电了，否则活不下去了
It must be now.
现在就得
Come forward. Slowly.
往前面来，慢慢地
- Be careful.  - Leave this to me.
- 小心点  - 把这交给我吧
You are absolutely crazy to trust them!
你觉得是疯了，居然相信他们!
You think so?
你这么觉得?
Then perhaps you and your colleagues
had better join him. Go on. Go on!
也许你和你的同事们最好跟他去，走，走!
- The girl stays with us.  - No!
- 这女孩留在我们这里  - 不!
She is our hostage.
他是我们的人质
Close the hatch.
关上舱门
You seem to be in trouble.
你看来有麻烦了
The energy...
能量
levels...are...low.
水平...低
We...will...survive.
我们...得...活下去
You will help us.
你得帮助我们
You will...help...us...
你得...帮助...我们
Yes. Yes, certainly.
是的，是的，当然了
- Jamie, Professor.
- You don't mean to say you're going to help them?
- Jamie, 教授  - 你不是想说你打算帮助他们吧?
Surely not. You can't support these creatures!
当然不能. 你不能帮这些怪物啊!
I think it best. Come on.
我已经想好了，来吧
Come along.
过来
That's it.
就这样
Do...you...understand...the...machine?
你...能...搞懂...那个...机器吗?
Yes. One moment.
是的，等一下
Have you taken leave of your senses?
Let's help Victoria.
你丧失判断力了吗? 我们来帮 Victoria
In a moment, Jamie.
等一下，Jamie
(DOCTOR) Now, are you ready?
现在， 你准备好了吗?
We will survive.
我们会活下去
We will sur...
我们会活...
Now, where would you rather
have him - in or out of there?
现在，你是愿意他待在里面呢，还是外面?
Oh, I see what you mean.
哦，我明白你的意思了
Only we must make sure
that he stays in there.
只是我们必须得确保他会待在里面
Do you really believe you can bargain
with those terrible Cybermen?
你真的相信你可以同那些可怕的赛博人讲条件?
That is our concern, not yours.
这是我们的事情，不关你事
I'm talking to him, not you.
我在跟他说话，不是你
They will have to agree to our plan.
他们将不得不同意我们的计划
Told you we shouldn't have touched it.
跟你说过我们本不该动它的
Yes. Turn it off. It's out of control.
是的．关掉它，失控了
(NOISE DIES DOWN)
It's taken over.
被他们接管了?
I think not.
我觉得没有
There must be some sort
of internal timing mechanism.
肯定有某种内部计时机制
Jamie, I hope you made
those ropes secure.
Jamie，我期望你把绳子绑牢了
The King of Beasties himself
couldnae get out of that?
那个怪兽之王不能自己跑出来吧?
Jamie, remind me to give you
a lesson in tying knots some time.
Jamie, 回头提醒我找个时间教你如何打结
What do you hope to gain from this?
你想通过这个达到什么目的?
- That does not concern you.
- They might as well know.
- 那不关你事  - 他们可能也知道
We are going to build a better world.
我们要建造一个更好的世界
(CALLUM) Better? But who for?
更好? 对谁更好?
I told you to watch the door.
我让你看好门的
Aagh!
啊!
Toberman.
Toberman.﻿
Victoria.
Victoria.﻿
- You have done well.  - Toberman!
- 你做得很好  - Toberman!
Silence.
安静
He is now under our control.
他现在处于我们控制之下了
Open the tombs.
打开墓室
No.
不
You have broken your promise.
你已经打破你的诺言了
Cybermen do not promise.
赛博人不做承诺
Such ideas have no value.
这样的观念没有价值
Open.
打开
No.
不
That gun will not harm me.
那把枪伤害不了我
Aagh!
啊!
Look what they've done.
看看他们干了啥
You are not like them. You're a man
like us. You must help us.
你跟他们不一样，你是我们的一员，你必须帮助我们
He has killed Kaftan.
You must help us.
他已经杀了 Kaftan, 你必须帮助我们
You will report to the surface.
你得向地面报告情况
(UNINTELLIGIBLE NOISES)
Jamie, the hatch!
Jamie, 舱门!
The gun, Jamie!
枪，Jamie!
There's another one, Doctor!
这里还有一个，博士!
(CRASHING)
Are there any more?
还有吗?
No. It's gone quiet.
I'll close the hatch.
没了，安静下来了．我去关上舱门
Wait a minute.
We'd better go down there.
等一下，我们最好下去
- Oh, no, not again!
- It's the only way to make sure.
- 噢不，别再下去了!   - 只有这样才能确认
- I'll go with you.
- No. You stay and look after Victoria.
- 我跟你一起去  - 不，你留在这里照看 Victoria
I'll take somebody else.
我另外带个人去
Toberman.
Toberman﻿
You see what these creatures
have done to you?
你看到这些怪物对你做了什么吧?
They've tried to make you like them.
Do you understand?
他们想把你变得跟他们一样，你明白吗?
They've tried to make you their slave.
They just want to use you.
他们试图把你变成他们的奴隶．他们想利用你
They are evil. Think of Kaftan.
他们是邪恶的，想想 Kaftan
- Evil!
- They must be destroyed, you see?
- 邪恶!   - 必须摧毁他们，你明白吗?
Evil must be destroyed.
邪恶必须被摧毁
Now, come.
现在，来吧
Destroyed!
摧毁!
Come on.
快来
Come on!
快来!
- Good luck.  - Thank you.
- 祝你好运  - 谢谢你
- Doctor, the gun.
- I shan't need that.
- 博士，枪   - 我应该不需要那个
Should have taken it.
你应该带着
- Aagh!
- Poor Mr Callum. How are you feeling?
- 啊!   - 可怜的 Callum. 你觉得怎么样?
I can't move my arm.
我动不了我的胳膊了
Move quietly.
慢慢移动
They're all dormant, see?
他们都休眠了，看?
Evil!
邪恶
No! Quietly. They're only asleep.
不! 安静点，他们只是睡着了
They're not frozen yet.
You watch them. I have things to do.
还没有被冻住．你看着他们，我还有事要做
Now, let me see.
现在，让我看看
Yes.
是了
The cryostat! You're freezing them!
低温保持器! 你要冻死他们啊!
Klieg!
Klieg!﻿
No! You'll wake them up!
不! 你会唤醒他们的!
That is exactly my intention.
那正是我的目的
You still don't understand, do you?
你还是没明白，是吗?
Their Controller is dead.
他们的管理员已经死了
Now I shall control them.
They will do what I say.
现在我来控制他们，我说什么他们就做什么
You see, Doctor.
你看，博士
Yours is the privilege to witness...
你获得了特权，来见证...
...for the first time the union between
mass power and my absolute intelligence.
...超级力量和我绝对智慧的第一次融合
Who is that?
谁?
Come out.
出来
Come out or I shall kill this man!
出来，否则我就杀了这个人!
Oh, it's you.
噢，是你
Go to that wall, all of you.
到墙那里去，你们全部
All of you!
你们全部过去!
No.
不
I have a better idea, a much better idea.
我有一个好主意，一个非常好的主意
I shall leave you to the Cybermen.
我要把你们留给赛博人
I'm sure they'll have some use for you.
我肯定他们拿你们有用
Or parts of you!
或者拿你的部件来用!
(KLIEG SCREAMS)
Quick, Jamie! These two levers together.
快，Jamie! 这两根杆一起拉
- I can't shift this one.
- What? You've got to trip that first.
- 我拉不动这个  - 什么? 你必须得先按那个
Last time they were frozen
for five centuries.
上一次他们冰冻了五个世纪
This time it must be forever.
这一次必须得是永远
Oh, Doctor!
噢，博士!
Here we are, Victoria, safe and sound.
Close the hatch.
我们上来了，Victoria, 安然无恙．关上舱门
There we are.
差不多了
Now then.
还有
The best thing about a machine
that makes sense -
一个机器最好的地方是...
you can very easily
make it turn out nonsense.
你可以很容易地把它变成废物
- Now I think you'd better all go outside.
- What are you going to do, Doctor?
- 现在我觉得你们最好都出去  - 你打算干什么，博士?
I'm going to re-electrify the main doors.
我要让主门重新上电
Only this time I'm going to include
the hatch and the control panel.
只不过这次要包含舱门和控制面板
Anyone touching any of them
will get a considerable shock.
任何人碰里面的一个，都会被电到休克
A fatal one. Now, everyone outside.
很致命的．现在，所有人都出去
Please take him with you.
I shall be glad to see him outside.
请把他带上跟你一起．我乐意见到他在外面
There we are. That's done.
好了，完成了
We just have to close the main doors
and the circuit is complete.
我们只要关上主门，电路就接通了
Thank goodness for that.
感谢上帝
Doctor.
博士
Doctor!
博士!
Jamie...
Jamie...﻿
You go that way. I'll go this way.
你去那边，我走这边
That gives us more of a chance.
这样胜算大些
When I say run, run.
我喊跑的时候，跑
Run!
跑!
Quickly!
快点!
Stop! We'll get a shock.
停下! 我们会被电的
We must find something to insulate.
That shoring timber.
我们必须找到绝缘的东西. 那些撑柱
Hurry up!
快点!
Hurry up, he's coming!
快啊，他要过来了!
We must keep him inside
我们必须把他关在里面
or all our work will be wasted.
要不然就前功尽弃了
- I can't hold mine!  - You must!
- 我顶不住了  - 必须顶住
Toberman!
Toberman!﻿
We must survive.
我们必须得活下去
You are evil.
你们是邪恶的
- Toberman, come away!
- You'll get killed, man!
- Toberman, 回来!  - 你会死的，伙计!
They shall never pass Toberman.
他们永远别想过 Toberman 这关
The door is closed.
门关上了